<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOps Thoughts and Ruminations</title>
    <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DevOps Thoughts and Ruminations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 20:54:11 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.linuxguru.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/projects/</guid>
      <description>Current Projects Song of the Day Is a Slack bot written in golang to provide jukebox support to group channels
MFA Is a small app for sytems to do totp keys (six digit mfa auth)
chef_k8s_docker is docker container to run Chef Cinc as a scalable container.
openvpn_k8s Access your local network from the outside world by running openvpn inside your k8s infrastructure!
k8s_tf An on-metal buildout of K8s including MetalLB, Cert-Manager, OpenEBS, internal docker registry and a fully scaleable Chef Cinc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is James! I&amp;rsquo;m a devops engineer by both trade and heart.
Tandy CoCo 2 My nerdlife started when a friend&amp;rsquo;s father brought home a teensy little computer named the Timex Sinclair 1000. characters. My opportunities with the machine were limited, but I became quicly hooked. Within a few months, I had my own computer of my own, a Tandy Color Computer 2, also known as a CoCo2. These machines, sold at Radio Shack, were rather limited in nature, having sported 16K of ram, a 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openebs Jiva Performance Timings</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/notes/openebs-timings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 20:54:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/notes/openebs-timings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introdution&#34;&gt;Introdution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sort of performance impact does Jiva replication have on drive performance
in K8s?  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find any recent, quick numbers, so I did some
quick and slopping testing for myself and was shocked by the results&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiva volumes with a replication factor of two saw an 83% drop in throughput
capacity. Three volume replication was even worse, weighing in at an 87%
drop in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly living in the land of default options, but
that much of a reduction in performance is dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph in K8s</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/notes/ceph_in_k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 12:25:05 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/notes/ceph_in_k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this note, I cover the details that I have uncovered thus far with rook and
ceph.  Ceph is a distributed filesystem that provides persistent storage,
S3-like object store and NFS support in one happy container.  Ceph can be quite
difficult to install the first couple times. Rook is intended to make deploying
Ceph much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Ceph&amp;rsquo;s resource requirements exceed that of my little home lab,
which consists of four systems with four cores and sixteen gigs of ram each.  I
managed to get a quick glance at prometheus just before the eviction storm and
saw that a whopping 72 pods were spun up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly exploring topic in depth will have to wait until I add more mores,
preferably with more ram and CPU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering cinc or chef Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/clustering_cinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 15:27:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/clustering_cinc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is the first of a series about setting up Cinc or Chef as as a
horizontally scalable service. This first post introduces the concept of which
parts of the service need to be broken out to provide for a cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 21:24:48 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
