<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOps Thoughts and Ruminations</title>
    <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DevOps Thoughts and Ruminations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 15:27:28 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.linuxguru.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/projects/</guid>
      <description>Current Projects Song of the Day Is a Slack bot written in golang to provide jukebox support to group channels
MFA Is a small app for sytems to do totp keys (six digit mfa auth)
chef_k8s_docker is docker container to run Chef Cinc as a scalable container.
openvpn_k8s Access your local network from the outside world by running openvpn inside your k8s infrastructure!
k8s_tf An on-metal buildout of K8s including MetalLB, Cert-Manager, OpenEBS, internal docker registry and a fully scaleable Chef Cinc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is James! I&amp;rsquo;m a devops engineer by both trade and heart.
Tandy CoCo 2 My nerdlife started when a friend&amp;rsquo;s father brought home a teensy little computer named the Timex Sinclair 1000. characters. My opportunities with the machine were limited, but I became quicly hooked. Within a few months, I had my own computer of my own, a Tandy Color Computer 2, also known as a CoCo2. These machines, sold at Radio Shack, were rather limited in nature, having sported 16K of ram, a 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering cinc or chef Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/clustering_cinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 15:27:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/clustering_cinc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is the first of a series about setting up Cinc or Chef as as a
horizontally scalable service. This first post introduces the concept of which
parts of the service need to be broken out to provide for a cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 21:24:48 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.linuxguru.net/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
